WAYNE LESTER BALLADOR

Iloilo City, PH • (+63)976 436 8175 • wlballador@gmail.com SOCIAL MEDIA and PR SPECIALIST

PROFESSIONAL PROFILE

As a creative problem solver with academic training in statistics and research, I have developed expertise in identifying and resolving complex challenges across various industries. I bring a unique perspective through my creative and technical writing, social media management, public relations, administration, logistics, and human resource management skills. As an active member of a non-profit organization dedicated to promoting local literature and culture, I strive to increase awareness and contribute to the enrichment of my community.

WORK EXPERIENCE

FREELANCE SOCIAL MEDIA CONSULTANT

2018 - PRESENT

- Developed customized social media strategies tailored to the client's goals and target audiences, optimizing engagement and brand visibility.
- Implemented data-driven tactics to analyze social media performance metrics, providing insightful recommendations for continual improvement and ROI enhancement.
- Cultivated and managed relationships with diverse clientele, delivering exceptional customer service and ensuring client satisfaction through effective communication and timely deliverables.

CONTENT WRITER - Remote

FEB 2023 - AUG 2023

Ranked PTE Ltd. (SBF Center, SG)

- Consistently generate and self-edit 20 ready-to-publish articles daily, providing high-quality content to Fortune 500 clients.
- Effectively generate content tailored to specific nuances of multiple English dialects, particularly in American, Australian, British, Canadian, and Indian English.
- Proactively participate in improving the company's operation to help develop effective and factual content to serve the clients better and elevate the company's quality of outputs.

PUBLIC RELATION CONSULTANT

JUN 2020 - SEP 2022

Prime Marketing (Iloilo City, PH)

- Established a thriving online community of over 5,000 potential customers by organizing engaging virtual events and creating daily, weekly, and monthly content for the company's social media pages.
- Implemented a Quality Assurance System based on KPIs and Branding Reviews to ensure the company's services and output consistently meet high-quality standards.
- Fostered successful relationships with local organizations and businesses, including artists, architects, establishments, venues, and malls, resulting in increased visibility and growth opportunities for the company.
- Led the company's 5th-anniversary celebration, increasing our social media reach and engagement by 215%, job and internship inquiries by 105%, and partnership invitations by 95%.

EDUCATION

University of the Philippines Visayas

Bachelor of Science in Statistics

SKILLS

- Content Creation (Creative and Technical)
- Human Resource Management
- Public Relations
- Administration and Logistics
- Social Media Management

- Google and Microsoft Document Software
- Photo and Video Editing
- Basic SEO
- Statistics, Research, and Development
- Proficient in English, Filipino and Hiligaynon